Congratulations on making it through this lesson.
恭喜你终于学完这节课了
We reviewed some foundational building blocks that you will see again and use when we
我们介绍了一些基本技能
translate academic papers into alpha ideas and then implement those ideas in code.
当你从学术论文中寻找 alpha 理念并用代码实现这些理念时 经常会用到这些技能
But let's just remember that, even after testing,
但是注意 即使经过测试后
if your alphas look promising,
alpha 看起来很有希望
this is really only the first stage of their lives so to speak.
但这也只是 alpha 生命周期的第一个阶段
Lets step back a bit and see how the search for alpha factors
我们再回来看看寻找 alpha 因子
fits into the big picture of the quant workflow.
在整个量化分析工作流程中所处的阶段
We first propose and generate alpha factors,
我们首先提出并创建 alpha 因子
then evaluate them to find those that might show some promise.
然后评估并选出有希望的 alpha 因子
Then we perform out-of-sample testing of
接着使用构建 alpha 向量时没用到的历史数据
the alpha factors using historical data that wasn't used to construct the alpha vector.
对 alpha 因子进行样本外测试
If that looks promising,
如果结果看起来不错
then we would conduct paper trading in which we don't use real money,
那么进行虚拟交易 这时候不使用真实资金
but we follow the factor as if we're making theoretical trays over
而是根据因子对新出现的实时市场数据
time on newly arriving live market data for some period.
进行虚拟交易并持续一段时间
If that showed promise,
如果表现得不出
then we would put the alpha into production in a real portfolio with real money.
则将 alpha 因子投入生产环境并投入真实资金
The alpha at that stage would be blended with
这时候需要将 alpha 因子与其他 alpha 整合到一起
other alphas and the final alpha vector would pass through a portfolio optimizer.
将最终 alpha 向量传入投资组合优化器中
We would likely start by giving that alpha factor a small weight in the combined vector,
一开始 在组合向量中 我们会为该 alpha 因子分配很小的权重
and given more weight if it performed and improved portfolio performance.
如果它能改进投资组合的业绩 则提高权重
We would monitor the alpha factor over time knowing that at some point,
我们将监控 alpha 因子随时间推移的效果
the factor's usefulness will erode because we're trading in a competitive market.
并且知道最终 alpha 因子的作用会消失 因为我们是在充满竞争的市场上交易
Then, we would remove the alpha factor and go back to
这时候 我们就会删除该 alpha 因子
the beginning to search for new promising alpha factors.
并继续从头寻找有希望的新 alpha 因子
Note that when I say "we" in those steps,
注意 当我在这些步骤中提到“我们”时
after the first one,
第一个“我们”之后的
the "we" could be a human portfolio manager or it
“我们”可能是人类投资组合经理
could be an artificially intelligent agent and AI.
也可能是人工智能代理 AI
Even in the first step,
甚至在第一步
we can utilize AI techniques to help us recover both these AI applications.
我们都可以利用 AI
The application for alpha generation and the AI application for
我们将在 AI 投资纳米学位课程的第二学期
portfolio construction in term two of the API for trading nano degree program.
讲解如何利用 AI 生成 alpha 以及创建投资组合
We will cover later stages of this process in future lessons.
我们将在后面的课程中讲解后续阶段
We will cover backtesting,
包括回溯测试
out-of-sample testing and other methods to avoid overfitting.
样本外测试和其他避免过拟合的方法
It can't be overstated how important out-of-sample testing is in practice.
怎么强调样本外测试在实践中的重要性都不为过
If our goal is to seek above average performance
如果我们的目标是在实际交易中
in real production trading with real money and real world constraints,
利用实际资金获得平均以上的业绩 并且受到实际约束条件的限制
then it is critically important to avoid overfitting to pass
那么一定要避免过拟合历史数据
data to the point that our alpha factors cannot generalize to current market conditions.
使 alpha 因子能够泛化到当前的市场条件
Even within the academic scientific community,
即使在学术研究领域
both in finance and in the general sciences,
包括金融和一般科学领域
there are serious discussions about
也有很多关于过拟合
overfitting and about validating the results of research.
以及验证研究成果的正式讨论
The rest of this lesson will focus on generating and evaluating alpha factors.
这节课的剩下部分将侧重于生成和评估 alpha 因子
But I do hope you keep in mind that it's perfectly normal if
但是如果你还有没听明白的地方 完全没关系
you feel the need to go back and review the concepts covered in this lesson.
你可以再回去复习这节课讲解的概念
I know there was quite a lot of material,
我知道讲解的内容很多
but I'm also very excited for you as you're learning the techniques and
但是很激动 因为你学习了
the type of thinking that real quant researchers deploy in their search for alpha.
真正的量化研究员在寻找 alpha 的过程中会用到的技巧和思维方式
See you in the next lesson.
下节课见